<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jShamsul.com (@jibone)</title>
    <description>Personal website of J.Shamsul (@jibone), a full stack web developer based in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</description>
    <link>http://jshamsul.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jshamsul.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Steve Jobs would never approve these iPhone5c cases</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I notice this while surfing on Apple&amp;#8217;s website. I was on the &lt;a href='http://www.apple.com/iphone-5c/'&gt;iPhone5c page&lt;/a&gt; looking at more pictures and reading specs. Just browsing around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple had introduced this funky looking iPhone5c cases where you can mismatch colors. Seems like fun. I then notice the word &amp;#8216;hon&amp;#8217; on one of those holes in the cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep thinking what is that word, until I eventually figured it out that it was the word &amp;#8216;iPhone&amp;#8217; with the letters &amp;#8216;iP&amp;#8217; and &amp;#8216;e&amp;#8217; blocked by the case and only &amp;#8216;hon&amp;#8217; is visible through one of the holes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this is such a small minor design issue and only effects the aesthetic just slightly, but if Steve Jobs is still around, I don&amp;#8217;t think that he would have approved this case design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Apple iPhone5c with case' src='http://assets.jshamsul.com/Screen-Shot-2013-09-14-at-4.37.32-PM.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 16:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jshamsul.com/opinions/2013/09/13/steve-jobs-would-never-approve-these-iphone5c-cases/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jshamsul.com/opinions/2013/09/13/steve-jobs-would-never-approve-these-iphone5c-cases/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apple Special Event: September 2013</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to write for an Apple/Mac centric blog, and each time there were any Apple Special Event, we would stayed up late at night looking at liveblogs and IRC channels. After that I would write a short post on what I thought of the announcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just for nostalgia sake I am doing one here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Apple Special Event' src='http://assets.jshamsul.com/apple-event-sept-2013.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality distortion field level in this one is very low. It might be because this is one of those rare times where all almost all the rumor websites actually got it right. What rumored to happen, happened. No surprises here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple introduces the iPhone5c priced lower then the premium iPhones, which people are jokingly calling it &amp;#8216;iPhone 5 cheap&amp;#8217;. The &amp;#8216;c&amp;#8217; here of course stands for &amp;#8216;colors&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Apple iPhone5c' src='http://assets.jshamsul.com/Screen-Shot-2013-09-14-at-4.38.23-PM.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These Lumia looking iPhones are unapologetically plastic. Even though it is plastic, from the videos and photos it looks very solidly builded. So does the Lumia phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple iPhones has always been a premium product. Other smart phone manufactures are killing it in the lower end market and it seems Apple wants a piece of the action. The lower priced iPhone might just do it. Might make the iPhone look &amp;#8216;hip&amp;#8217; to the younger consumers. It&amp;#8217;s priced towards them too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I think the real reason for Apple to introduce a new line of lower end iPhone is to make the next generation of Apple&amp;#8217;s current line of iPhone looks more premium. They even colored it gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Apple iPhone5s' src='http://assets.jshamsul.com/Screen-Shot-2013-09-14-at-4.39.16-PM.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s always been the case where an &amp;#8216;s&amp;#8217; version of the iPhone is just a spec upgrade, and it looks exactly like the non-&amp;#8217;s&amp;#8217; version. How would people know you have the latest and greatest iPhone when what you have looks the same as the previous version? Apple address this by making a gold colored iPhone of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This iPhone5s is just a test run for the fingerprint scanner. If the technology works flawlessly, I bet we will be seeing this on all of Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However it seems Apple trust the scanner enough that you can have it as a verification for an iTunes Store purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a short announcement and there was no &amp;#8216;one more thing.&amp;#8217; I think that have always been a Steve Jobs thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jshamsul.com/opinions/2013/09/10/apple-special-event-september-2013/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jshamsul.com/opinions/2013/09/10/apple-special-event-september-2013/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scraping Wikileaks for The Global Intelligence Files</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wikileaks begin publishing what they call &amp;#8221;&lt;a href='https://search.wikileaks.org/gifiles/?rl'&gt;The Global Intelligence Files&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221;, which is a collection of over five million e-mails from &lt;a href='http://www.stratfor.com/'&gt;Stratfor&lt;/a&gt;, a &amp;#8216;global intelligence&amp;#8217; firm headquartered in Texas. The emails are from July 2004 to late December 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stratfor is a company that fronts as and intelligence publisher, but provides confidential intelligence services to large corporations such as Bhopal&amp;#8217;s Dow Chemical Co., Lockheed Martin, Northrop Grumman, Raytheon and government agencies including US Department of Homeland Security, US Marines and US Defense Intelligence Agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Wikileaks the emails reveal the inner workings of Stratfor. It shows their web of informers, pay-off structure, payment laundering techniques and other methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I&amp;#8217;ve read, which is only the emails in the release batch that says - &amp;#8220;US Intelligence Firm Stratfor Eyes Malaysia&amp;#8221;, it seems that Stratfor gathers all sort of information from various sources, on various matters, but mostly are on the country&amp;#8217;s stability which includes political issues and the country&amp;#8217;s oil and gas industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources ranges from publicly available publications to confidential informations from their informant. They then analyze them and publish an in-depth report either for their newsletter, their website or for whoever their clients might be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikileaks have started releasing the emails back in early 2012. They release it batch by batch. The recent release had caught my attention. It&amp;#8217;s the batch of emails marked as &amp;#8220;US Inteliigence Firm Startfor Eyes Malaysia&amp;#8221;. Would love to read what these people in this &amp;#8216;global intelligence&amp;#8217; firm has to say about Malaysia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a little script that scrapes Wikileaks to save all these email locally, so I don&amp;#8217;t have to keep going to the wikileaks website to read them. I compiled all 2235 of the emails in a zip file. The script is on my &lt;a href='http://github.com/jibone/nancy'&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested and you can download the compile zip file &lt;a href='http://assets.jshamsul.com/downloads/stratfor_malaysia.zip'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Scraping Wikileaks Global Intelligence Files' src='http://assets.jshamsul.com/Screen-Shot-2013-09-01-at-2.37.20-PM.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='so_what_is_in_all_the_emails'&gt;So what is in all the emails?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have yet to go through all the emails, but from what I had read, nothing much. Bulk of the emails are them sharing news clippings and publications. Marked as OS which probably means &amp;#8216;Open Source&amp;#8217;, sources that are published and accessible publicly. Its interesting to see which news interest them though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a &lt;a href='https://search.wikileaks.org/gifiles/?viewemailid=72394'&gt;few emails&lt;/a&gt; that start with this formatted header :-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
SOURCE: ML101 
ATTRIBUTION: Stratfor sources in Kuala Lumpur 
SOURCE DESCRIPTION: Editor, Malaysiakini.com, and confederation partner 
PUBLICATION: as needed 
SOURCE RELIABILITY: B 
ITEM CREDIBILITY: 2 
SPECIAL HANDLING: none 
DISTRIBUTION: analysts 
SOURCE HANDLER: Lena 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems that one of their sources is the editor of Malaysiakini.com editor. While I am not a journalist, I believe that it&amp;#8217;s common practice for journalists to exchange info among themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think there is anything nefarious in this emails. Most probably they are taking account of the source&amp;#8217;s opinion on certain issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lena Bell seems interesting. It seems that she is most of the source handler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='read_it_yourself'&gt;Read it yourself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://assets.jshamsul.com/downloads/stratfor_malaysia.zip'&gt;Here is the zip collection&lt;/a&gt; of &amp;#8221;&lt;a href='https://search.wikileaks.org/gifiles/?relid=668#searchresult'&gt;US Intelligence Firm Stratfor Eyes Malaysia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221; or head on over to Wikileaks to read these and many more internal emails of Stratfor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jshamsul.com/labs/2013/08/31/scraping-wikileaks-for-the-global-intelligence-files/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jshamsul.com/labs/2013/08/31/scraping-wikileaks-for-the-global-intelligence-files/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where is the iOS Simulator?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t do much work on Xcode, although I&amp;#8217;ve always wanted to do some native iOS work. One of the Xcode utility app which I use from time to time is the iOS simulator. I use the Safari in the iOS simulator to test how a website would look like in a mobile form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had updated my Xcode to version 4.6.3 and the iOS Simulator is nowhere to be found. After some Googling, it seems that Apple had packaged the iOS Simulator app into Xcode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That does not mean that you can&amp;#8217;t use the iOS Simulator without launching Xcode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need to do is find the Xcode.app in your Application folder, control + click on the app to show the folder menu and choose &amp;#8216;Choose Package Contents&amp;#8217;, this will open a Finder window with the contents of Xcode app. You will see a folder named &amp;#8216;contents&amp;#8217;. The path to your iPhone/iOS simulator is in -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='html'&gt;Contents / Application / iPhone Simulator.app
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That however is just an alias, control + click and choose &amp;#8216;Show Original&amp;#8217; if you want to know where the actual app is at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All other Xcode development utilities are all now bundled inside the Xcode app. You can drag the app out to your Dock for easy access. That way, you don&amp;#8217;t have to launch Xcode if you need to use the iOS Simulator app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='apps_inside_another_app'&gt;Apps inside another app?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In NeXTSTEP and OpenStep, which are what OSX descended from, applications and its related resources including the executable can be bundled in a directory and appeared as a single file to use, i.e. &amp;#8220;Application Name.app&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jshamsul.com/developments/2013/08/19/where-is-the-iOS-simulator/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jshamsul.com/developments/2013/08/19/where-is-the-iOS-simulator/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Wordpress to Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve decided to switch from a self-hosted Wordpress setup to Jekyll generated static site hosted on Github. I&amp;#8217;ve been a long time user of Wordpress, as a blog-centric content management software I think it&amp;#8217;s a great product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://wordpress.org'&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; can be installed on most shared hosting setup. As long as you have PHP and MySQL you are all set. Wordpress is the most used open-source software for creating websites. Tried and tested. So why did I change?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://jekyllrb.com'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is a simple blog-aware static site generator. What it does is it takes a directory of text files written either in Markdown or Textile, render it with Liquid template converters and spits out an entire static website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll splits out HTML files that makes the entire website. As long as you have a web server that serves up HTML files you are set. There is not need for MySQL databases, setting up tables and all that stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no &amp;#8216;admin&amp;#8217; panel you need to login to update your blog. You write your post in a text file, format it with Markdown (or Textile), run Jekyll command line to generate all the static pages ready to publish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can upload this generated file to your server, but there is a much better way. You can commit this files with Git, and push it to your remote Git repo on your server. Even better, you can also use Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github support Jekyll with their Github pages. Github store and serve your static website. This is what I went for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of not having any &amp;#8216;backend&amp;#8217;. There is no secure admin panel to login into, I can write my blog post with any text editor, format it with Markdown. When I&amp;#8217;m done with my post, I just need to &lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt; and it&amp;#8217;s up. Jekyll is definitely more developer friendly and works well with Git driven workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see how this seems intimidating to a non-technical person. Wordpress maybe a better choice for a more traditional workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am just starting to play around with Jekyll, will update on this topic more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jshamsul.com/updates/2013/08/15/from-wordpress-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jshamsul.com/updates/2013/08/15/from-wordpress-to-jekyll/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcoming Lana to this world</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today marks the beginning of a new chapter in my life, Not only that I am a son and a husband, I am now a dad. Last year about the same time, I married my lovely wife, Nurul Izwa. This year we are blessed with our daughter Lana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='how_do_you_feel_now'&gt;How do you feel now?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got asked that a lot. It feels different that&amp;#8217;s for sure. My priority in life has changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep down I feel that my time is running out. When we were young we felt invincible. We felt that the world is ours for the taking. We do stuff, risky stuff and stupid stuff without considering any of there consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now with a daughter to take care of, I no longer felt that way. The world is not mine for the taking any more, it&amp;#8217;s hers. It&amp;#8217;s her world now, we are just living in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My time is up, soon it&amp;#8217;s going to be her time. All we as parents can do is to hand down to her as much wisdom as we can. Wisdom that we have collected all these years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That, together with the wisdom she that she finds for herself, she is going to conquer the world, take on any challenges life may bring to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we will right there supporting her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just felt like I should write something about my daughter Lana. Still getting use to saying that two words, &amp;#8216;my daughter&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jshamsul.com/personal/2013/07/07/welcoming-lana-to-this-world/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jshamsul.com/personal/2013/07/07/welcoming-lana-to-this-world/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yet another redesign</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve lost count how many times I did a redesign to this website of mine. One thing for sure is that the more redesign I do, the less of a ‘design’ it has become. Here you see me obsessed in minimalistic white-space heavy design. Less is not just more, less is better. Sort of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also decided to adopt &lt;a href='http://html5boilerplate.com/'&gt;html5boilerplate&lt;/a&gt;, not entirely just most of the basic ideas and snippets from that project. I even keep the bright pink highlighting color, go ahead highlight my text. Since I love doing my CSS with Sass now, I use this little project on Github, &lt;a href='https://github.com/grega/HTML5-Boilerplate-with-Sass'&gt;HTML5-Boilerplate-with-Sass&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend a large amount of time arguing with myself while doing this theme. Should I use a light border to separate items, or just a big fat white-space. You can see which route I took.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some snapshots of how this website looks previously:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='screenshot' src='http://jshamsul.com/assets/Screen-Shot-2012-02-04-at-9.26.20-AM.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='screenshot' src='http://jshamsul.com/assets/Screen-Shot-2012-02-04-at-9.26.46-AM.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='screenshot' src='http://jshamsul.com/assets/Screen-Shot-2012-02-04-at-9.26.20-AM.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also decided to share the code. The theme code are on a &lt;a href='https://github.com/jibone/wp-jshamsul.com'&gt;public Github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2012 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jshamsul.com/updates/2012/02/05/yet-another-redesign/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jshamsul.com/updates/2012/02/05/yet-another-redesign/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekend Web Project - Crowded</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A silly little website that searches Foursquare checkins at a certain area on the map. It finds trending venues and display it on the map. You might have guessed it already, I’m just playing around with the Foursquare API. Try it out:- &lt;a href='http://lab.jshamsul.com/crowded'&gt;lab.jshamsul.com/crowded&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Screenshot' src='http://jshamsul.com/assets/Screen-shot-2011-10-16-at-8.19.56-PM.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is not trending venue, use the form to jump to a certain location. List of trending venues are displayed once you are at a location where there are a lot of checkins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some technology and API used for this project are, Foursquare API, Google Map API v3, Google Map Utility Library MarkerClusterer. Codes are up on Github, if you want to have a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this thing have legs? probably not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jshamsul.com/labs/2011/10/17/weekend-web-project-crowded/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jshamsul.com/labs/2011/10/17/weekend-web-project-crowded/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I am loving the Metro UI from Microsoft</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Those who knows me personally probably know that I am an Apple/Mac centric kind of person. No, I’m not a &amp;#8216;fanboy&amp;#8217; but I have been called that from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secretly however, I have a crush on the Metro UI design that Microsoft is adopting for their OS on new devices. Even though on the Wikipedia page it says that the Metro principles were use as early as Microsoft Encrata 95, but I think it was the Zune that Metro really makes its first appearance and people start noticing it. And now you can see the user interface on Windows Phone 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder how the thought process for this new Metro UI came to be. It is as if Microsoft designer folks looked at Apple and decides to go the very opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has rounded corners in their icons, buttons, UI containers and other UI elements. Microsoft’s Metro have sharp edges on most of their UI elements. Apple’s iOS is about icons of apps, Microsoft’s Metro decides not to use icons instead live tiles that apps can push informations to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metro to me is more then just a theme you slap on an OS or software. It’s a design philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Metro is our design language. We call it metro because it is modern and clean. It is fast and in motion. It’s about content and typography. And it’s entirely authentic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are annoyed with the whole lack of UI in Metro, but it is in fact for that reason of less UI chrome that I love Metro. There are few core principles that defines the Microsoft Metro Language, and I’ll try to go through some of it here pretending that I know a thing or two about design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Windows 8 Screenshot' src='http://assets.jshamsul.com/Screen-shot-2011-09-22-at-12.15.29-PM.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='typography'&gt;Typography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typography plays an important role in the whole Metro design language. The slim Segoe based font family fits right in with the sharp edges of the design element. It is not just about beautiful fonts for text labels, it is functional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the right balance of weight, white space and positioning it creates a visual hierarchy without the need for extra UI elements. In Metro it&amp;#8217;s clear that which text is the title and which are the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='motion'&gt;Motion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transition are and important element to a UI design. It tells the story and user knows what to expect. Metro has a consistent set of animations that are not just pretty to look at but serve a functional purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='content_not_chrome'&gt;Content not Chrome&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my favorite. I always think that content itself can be the interface. All other UI containers and elements just get in the way. Content has to always be the top priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metro really implement this to its core. No chrome no distraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='honesty'&gt;Honesty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metro design language is design for the digital. Metro knows that it is designed for the digital device and Metro does not pretend to be something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A note taking application does not need to look like a Moleskine note book. A calendar application does not need to look like a leather bound desk calendar. Metro does not pretend to be something it is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='moving_forward'&gt;Moving forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope Microsoft will move forward with this new paradigm shift of digital interface. This is the most innovative thing coming from Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody ever gets it right the first time, Metro has it shares of haters. I hope Microsoft will still keep pushing this, and keep on going in this path.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jshamsul.com/opinions/2011/09/22/i-am-loving-the-metro-ui-from-microsoft/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jshamsul.com/opinions/2011/09/22/i-am-loving-the-metro-ui-from-microsoft/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Petknode - it does not make any sense</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;These few days, Malaysian cat lovers, Kitteh defenders alike were up in arms over what had happened to over 200 pet felines that were supposed to be under the care of Petknode, a company that offers cat boarding services. These are pet cats and not stray cats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the long Raya holiday, pet owners had send their cats to Petknode while they and their family went to their hometown to celebrate the Raya festive with the rest of the extended family. It’s a long known Raya ‘balik kampung’ tradition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not to familiar with Petknode, but I’ve heard of them before. I’ve heard good things about them before, from those who had send their pet cats to them. So this whole incident came as a shock to some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Petknode had took in over 200 cats and those cats were left in their cages for over 9 days or so with out any supervision. No food or water for the cats. Even prisoners have their daily meals, it’s as if the cats were left there to,… die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the animal lovers are still in rage over what had happened. I put the rage and anger aside and try to think of what or why Petknode did what they did. Nobody is pure evil, there is always some sort of reasoning behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can believe that they just leave the cats for over a week and thought that things would be fine when the owners come to pick their pets later after the holiday was over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first thought is that they are running a con job. Take the money and leave. However, to my knowledge Petknode have been operating for quite sometime and there were no complaints before this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine that over 200 cats were send by their owner to Petknode. This cat boarding service is a very lucrative business in a long term. Why would the Petknode owners jeopardize what seems to be a very profitable lucrative long term business for a making just a little quick buck? Are they that short sighted?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this were a con job, then they the Petknode owners are the stupidest con men ever. They should already disappear, out of the country type of disappear, they should have already run away with the few bucks they had made over the Raya promotion. Yet they are still here, the police are able to get them at their house?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That does not make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second thought is that they had took in more cats than they can handle. This is obviously so. Maybe they had hire some illegal foreign workers to take care of the basic necessities of the cats while they were gone for the Raya holiday. The illegal foreign workers then had run away for some reason leaving the cats just like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, if that was the case, didn’t they as the employers ever called and check? Can’t they come back if something were wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That does not make sense either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third thought came to mind. Maybe they, the Petknode owner were running from someone? Maybe they had loaned some money from loan sharks and were unable to pay them back. They thought that by doing a Raya promotion and taking in 200 cats would be enough to save their ass, but it is not enough. It always isn’t enough when dealing with loan sharks. Fear of what the loan sharks would do to them they run and leave the cats under their care behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that people do make unreasonable decisions when pressured by loan sharks. Fear of their life, or fear of the public humiliation they might face with the loan sharks. It’s better to get sued by pet owners then to face the loan sharks? Who knows…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will never know what or why and I am not saying that I know either. I am not trying to justified their action either. This is just me trying to make some sense over what had happen with the Petknode fiasco.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jshamsul.com/opinions/2011/09/06/petknode-it-does-not-make-any-sense/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jshamsul.com/opinions/2011/09/06/petknode-it-does-not-make-any-sense/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
